# **Azmine Toushik Wasi**

+880 1521 526792 | azminetoushik.wasi@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn | Kaggle | GitHub | Website</u>

## Summery

An idealist with distinguished experience, and expertise in Programming, IT Automation, Design, Ed-Tech, Product & Content Development and Project Management. Currently, exploring Data Science, Machine Learning and IT Automation. Love to learn new things, improve existing skills, experiment with acquired skills and challenge my capabilities.

## **Technical Skills**

**Programming Skills:** Python, R, C

Data Related Skills: Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, SAS Visual Business Analytics, SQL, NumPy,

Pandas, Matplotlib, Statistics

Machine Learning Skills: Regression, Classification, NLP, Time Series

Education		
Feb 2020 - Present	Bachelor of Science (Engr.) in Industrial and Production Engineering Shahjalal University Of Science And Technology • Expected to complete in 2024	
Work Experience		
2021 - Present	<ul> <li>Manager- BasaKhujo (Self-employed)</li> <li>Developing business, financial, operational strategy.</li> <li>Oversee R&amp;D. Analyze and research about data, services, product, business intelligence.</li> </ul>	
Apr 2022 – Present Started working here at Jun 2021	<ul> <li>Project Executive - 10 Minute School (Part time)</li> <li>Content Development - Quality Assurance - Performance, SEO Performance, Strategic Development.</li> <li>Point of Contact, 10MS Jobs Content Management (Freelance)   Worked in 20+ different projects</li> <li>Lead, Content Design Team, 10MS Jobs - Admissions</li> <li>Led/Co-ordinated 15+ projects with different stakeholders.</li> </ul>	
Sep 2021 – Feb 2022	<ul> <li>Live-Class Resource Executive - Shikho (Part time)</li> <li>Preparation and quality 500+ Live-Class materials.</li> <li>Content and performance analytics.</li> </ul>	
	Organizational/Voluntary Experience	
Sep 2022 – Jan 2022 Started working here at Nov 2020	Wing Director, Technical Facilities Enhancement – Black Brains • Lead, Micro-course and App Product Development	

- Lead, Micro-course and App Product Development
- Regular technical R&D and improvements.

Sep 2021 - Feb 2022

## Judge, The Queen's Commonwealth Essay Competition 2021 – Royal Commonwealth Society

Judge of the competition with 26,000+ submission

Mar 2019 - Oct 2021

## Information Technology Manager - Bangladesh Youngster **Social Organization**

Developed App, Website and other IT Structures for the organization and increased productivity by 350%.

#### **Other Skills**

Data Analytics, Visualization, Microsoft Word – Powerpoint - Access, Google Tools, Communication, Team Management, Teamwork, Proficient in Bangla and English

## **Virtual Internships**

Aug 2021	<ul> <li>Data Analytics Internship   EntryLevel</li> <li>Data Analytics , Business Modeling</li> <li>Used MS Excel, Power BI</li> </ul>
Jun 2021	<ul> <li>Engineering: Undergraduate &amp; Masters   Forage - Microsoft</li> <li>Software Engineering, Design, Engineering thinking</li> <li>Data Analytics , Business Modeling</li> </ul>
Mar 2021	<ul> <li>Data@ANZ Program   Forage - ANZ</li> <li>Data Science (Used Scikitlearn - Linear Regression)</li> <li>Exploratory Data Analysis - Predictive Analytics</li> </ul>
Apr 2021	<ul> <li>Open-Access Data Science &amp; Advanced Analytics Forage   BCG</li> <li>Data Science and Problem Structuring</li> <li>EDA, Feature Engineering, Mathematical Modeling</li> </ul>

#### **Prizes and Awards**

GDN Presenta - Champion | Podiam 1.0 - 2nd Runners Up National High School Programming Contest - 2016 and 2017 - Regional Winner; National Top 30 in both

Inter School & College Programming Contest '19 – **Regional (3<sup>rd</sup>) - National Top 30**Queens Commonwealth Essay Competition 2019 – **Silver Award**National Earth Science Olympiad 2019 – **National Winner**Bangladesh Physics Olympiad 2019 Comilla Region - **5th** 

## **Learning and Certifications**

## Professional Certificates (Coursera):

- DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer
- SAS Visual Business Analytics

## <u>Google Career - Professional Certificates</u> (Coursera):

- Data Analyst
- IT Automation with Python
- Project Management

#### **Edx Courses:**

- IBMx DS0105EN: Data Science Tools
- Harvardx PH526x: Using Python for Research

## **Coursera Specializations Completed:**

- Python 3 Programming U.Mich
- Data Analyst IBM
- Machine Learning DeepLearning.ai
- Dee Learning DeepLearning.ai
- Applied Data Science with Python
- Data Analysis and Visualization

## **DataCamp Learning Paths Completed:**

- <u>Career Tracks:</u> Python Programmer, Data Analyst, Data Scientist
- <u>Skill Tracks</u>: Machine Learning Scientist with Python, Python Programming, Python Fundamentals, Data Manipulation, Visualization, NLP, Time series
- Python, Data, Analysis Advanced
   Level Proficiency DataCamp Certified

## **LinkedIn Learning Paths Completed:**

- · Software Developer
- Data Analyst
- · Financial Analyst

## **IBM Developer Skills Network Programs:**

 Data and AI – CP4D Journey – Intermediate

## **Frecodecamp.org Certifications:**

Data Analysis with Python